JUSTIN MARTINELLI

Brooklyn, NY 11230 | 1-718-757-6212 | justinmartinelli1@gmail.com | github.com/justinm-nyc

PROFILE

Full-stack software engineer with 3+ years' experience designing and building user interfaces for web and mobile applications. I am passionate about designing frontends and making wireframes come to life, but I also enjoy the complexities of creating backends and APIs for quick smooth data retrieval. During my time at Oracle, I worked with many of Oracle's cloud products to create modern applications to show customers Oracle's cloud capabilities. I am versatile, I have phenomenal time management skills, and I'm curious by nature. Seeking to take the next career step with a respected organization and expand my technical skills and experience.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Languages: (proficient): JavaScript, Git (familiar): Python, Java
- **Web Development:** (*proficient*): Node.js, Express.js, Vue, RESTful APIs, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap (familiar): React
- Databases: Oracle Autonomous Database, PL/SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Tableau, SQLPro, MongoDB
- Cloud: Oracle Cloud
- **DevOps:** Docker, Kubernetes
- **Spoken Languages:** English(*nαtive*), Spanish(*fluent*)

CERTIFICATIONS

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure 2018 Certified Architect Associate

March 2019

EMPLOYMENT

Android Developer (Temp), Travilous

March 2020 – Present

- Convert the Travilous iPhone applications user experience into a user experience and design created specifically for Android devices in a remote work environment
- Recode activities from Swift into Android Kotlin

Cloud Solution Engineer, Oracle Corporation

August 2018 – December 2019

- Architected and built customer solutions using full-stack development, creating APIs, and Oracles latest Cloud Computing services including chatbot, blockchain, autonomous database, serverless computing services and more
- Converted client needs into easy-to-understand software solutions, aiding in the sales team in closing midmarket deals
- Modernized company technologies and migrating them to Oracle's cloud products and thus slashing client costs, improving their data security, and virtually eliminating unplanned data center outages

Junior Software Developer, RAISE/NSF

May 2017 - May 2018

- Improved the comprehension of ecology for incarcerated teenagers by developing and designing ecology appbook components science curriculum using Swift, SQLPro, XCode, Sketch, and GitHub in an agile environment
- Transformed written textbook descriptions and wireframes into intuitive and interactive widget lessons

KTech Tech Services Intern, KPMG US

June 2017 – August 2017

• Devised a process to efficiently migrate all office employees from Windows 7 to Windows 10 and wipe hard drives and thus allow more hours to be allocated to perform higher priority tasks

 Supported ongoing operations, automation, integration, troubleshooting, and maintenance of systems in a fast-paced team-oriented environment

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

Oracle Enterprise Simulator

Summer 2019

- Lead in developing software that simulates an enterprise workload of up to 10,000 users running transactions on Oracles Autonomous Transaction Processing Database
- Created both the frontend and backend that allows the user to select either an eCommerce dataset or a Healthcare Survey dataset, then choose a pattern of user activity such as burst, ramp, or static, and then select the number of virtual users that will be transacting against the database
- Utilized Oracle Serverless technology, Node.js, Express.js, Vue.js, Bootstrap, Oracle Kubernetes Engine, Docker

Oracle Scientific Imaging

Spring 2019

- Developed scientific imaging software to save images captured from a microscope and report documents on the Oracle cloud and to save metadata in Oracle's blockchain service
- Design RESTful backend server enabling reports and microscope captured images to be saved to Oracle Object Storage and document and image information to Oracle Block Storage
- Utilized Node.js, Express.js, Vue.js, Oracle Blockchain Cloud Service and Oracle Object Storage

INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCE

Wildlife Sanctuary Volunteer, Parque Municipal Summit, Panamá

January 2019 – February 2019

- Participated in animal care and rehabilitation with the veterinarian in the animal clinic
- Assisted in preparation and distribution of food for all animals, cleaning, and preparation of enclosures, cleaning of paths
 and trails, eliminating invasive plants, and the placement of germinated plant species into bags
- Reduce the load on the low number of employees of the sanctuary

EDUCATION

University of Massachusetts Amherst

September 2014 – May 2018

• Major: Computer Science, B.S. (Cumulative GPA: 3.4)